inverness-courier.co.uk 2019-07-23

# Privacy Policy - SPP Media Group

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Please note that there may be other privacy policies that apply to certain services we provide. Please read these when you register or subscribe for these services.

If you have any queries about this notice or would like to make requests to exercise your rights, please email [privacy@sppgroup.co.uk](mailto:privacy@sppgroup.co.uk)

* * *

### 1\. What is covered by the Privacy Policy?

  * Your privacy and safety is important to us. We do not collect any more personal information than is necessary for the operation of the Websites. 
  * By using the Websites and submitting your information to us, you consent to the use and disclosure by us of your information as set out in this privacy policy. By sending us your details to post on the Websites, you are deemed to agree to such posting. We may change this privacy policy at any time by posting changes online.
  * This privacy policy does not apply to sites that you access via a link to our Websites; you should check the privacy policies of such sites.

* * *

### 2\. What security is in place to keep your personal data secure?

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent unauthorised access to the information you provide, and promise to keep your data safe and private.

* * *

### 3\. What personal information is collected by us, and do we use cookies?

The information we collect via the Website may include:

  * any personal details you provide to us through completing electronic forms and sending emails, such as your name, address and telephone number; and data recorded by the Website which allows us to recognise you and your preferred settings. This saves you from re-entering information on return visits to the Website. Such data is recorded locally on your computer through the use of cookies (small test files which contain a unique identification number written to a user's hard disc and read by a server program). Most browsers can be programmed to reject or warn you before downloading cookies and information regarding this may be found in your browser's "help" facility. 

If you post your information on any of our Websites, your information may be collected and processed by other users of the Websites. We have no control over how these users may process your data.

* * *

### 4\. Is it possible to access and browse our Website without disclosing personal data?

Yes, some areas of the Website can be accessed without disclosing personal information. However, other services offered by the Websites will ask for personal details.

* * *

### 5\. How do we use the personal information we gather?

Any personal information we collect from the Websites will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws.

Such personal data may be used to provide you with details of our services, to provide marketing information if you indicate that you want to receive such information and to help us analyse site usage in order to develop the Websites and for our general administrative purposes.

* * *

### 6\. Do we disclose our users' personal information to third parties?

We will not without your consent sell, share or transfer your personal information to third parties except as set out in this Privacy Policy or that we are required to do by law. Such third parties will not be allowed to use your personal information for their own purposes.

* * *

### 7\. Do you have the right to access and/or change the information we hold about you?

Yes. In order to receive a copy of any information that we currently hold about you or to change such information please send your contact details to [privacy@spp-group.com]() or write to the following address:

Scottish Provincial Press

New Century House

Stadium Road

Inverness IV1 1FG

* * *

### Cookie Policy

**Introduction**

By accessing and using our website or other services, you are agreeing to the terms of this policy and our privacy policy. Please do read these policies carefully so you know what we are doing with your information.

* * *

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small files of letters and numbers. These files are either stored in the memory of your computer or other device such as mobile phones or tablet devices (these cookies are generally known as session cookies) or are placed on the hard drive of your device (generally known as persistent cookies).

Cookies are created when you visit a website that uses cookies. Cookies are commonly used by websites to help the user's browsing experience and provide more information about the user's experience and interests. This information is generally used to make content, services and advertising more relevant and useful during future visits.

For more details about cookies and details of how to delete and disable cookies you can visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) and also see our section on more information and turning cookies off below.

* * *

### How do our websites use cookies?

All of our websites uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website and to provide increased functionality when you are using our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our website and our services.

Unless you have adjusted your browser settings to refuse cookies, our systems will issue cookies as soon you visit our website or access other services. If you have switched off cookies then some of the functionality of our website or services may not be available to you.

Please note that not all the cookies on our sites are set by us but we have indicated in this policy where cookies are set by third parties.

* * *

### What cookies are placed on our websites?

The cookies on our website are mainly functional and analytical cookies.

**Analytical cookies**

Analytical cookies allow us to recognise and to count the number of visitors to our website, to see how visitors move around the website when they are using it and to record which content viewers view and are interested in. This helps us to determine how frequently particular pages and advertisements are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website and/or services. This helps us to improve the service which we offer to you by helping us make sure our users are finding the information they are looking for, by providing anonymised demographic data to third parties in order to target advertising more appropriately to you, and by tracking the success of advertising campaigns on our website.

**Functional cookies**

Functional cookies relate to the functionality of our website and allow us to improve the services we offer to you through our website, for example:

  * by recording your opinion or action (e.g. where you have voted in a poll);
  * by allowing you to carry information across pages of our website to avoid you having to re-enter information or interact more quickly;
  * to allow you to access stored information if you have registered with us;
  * by recognising your preferences when you return to our website(s);
  * by enabling us to serve the appropriate regionalised service relevant to your location; or
  * by ensuring that any adverts which you view on our website are not repeated within a short space of time.

**What functional and analytical cookies do we use?**

We have set out below the main functional and analytical cookies that we use:

**Name of Cookie**

**What does it do?**

Login

We use this cookie when you login to post comments and request that we remember you for future visits

UserName 

We use this cookie when you do not login to post comments and request that we remember your username for future visits

UserEmail

We use this cookie when you do not login to post comments and request that we remember your email for future visits

Polls

We use this cookie when you vote in a poll so we can track people voting twice.

CookieCheck 

We use this cookie to see if you have seen the cookie alert before, so we don't show it again.

We also use analytical cookies which are operated on our behalf by the organisations listed below to help us deliver our services.

* * *

**Organisation setting the cookie**

**Name of cookie**

**What does it do?**

Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics tool provided by Google Ireland Limited ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to help the website analyse how users use the website. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website and your current IP address will be transmitted by your browser to and will be stored by Google on servers in the United States and other countries. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activity and provide us with other services relating to website activity and internet usage. The IP address collected through Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google.

_utma

This cookie helps us determine the number of unique visitors to our website.

_utmz

This cookie helps us determine the referral method for people visiting our website. This helps us to analyse the traffic arriving at our website and to determine which are the most popular routes (e.g. direct, search engine search, email link).

_utmb

We use this cookie to help us to record the length of individual sessions from our users on our website. Each time you move to a new page within our website within 30 minutes of arriving the cookie updates so that we know that you are still actively using our website within a single session.

_utmc

Similar to _utmb, we use this cookie to help us record the length of individual sessions on our website.

* * *

**Cookies that are set by third parties**

From time to time, Our Websites may sell advertising space to third parties who may deploy cookies to gather information about users to target their advertising to those users.

The website may include functionality enabling you to interact with the site using social media tools such as Facebook or twitter. Such interactions may require the use of cookies by Facebook.com or twitter.com to recognise you as a user of those platforms and match your actions with your social media account. You can find out more detail about Facebook's use of data at the [Facebook Data Use Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) and more detail about twitter's use of data in the [Twitter Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy).

* * *

**When do our cookies expire?**

Except for essential cookies, most of the cookies on our websites expire at the end of your current session on our website. However, some of our cookies have an extended lifespan which ranges from 1 day to 26 years. Where we specify that the cookie being used is a flash cookie, please note that flash cookies do not expire.

* * *

**Where can I find more information about cookies, and how do I turn cookies off or delete cookies?**

Find out more about cookies including how to disable/enable and delete them at the following website [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

You can block most cookies (except for Flash cookies) by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our sites, or you may experience reduced functionality when accessing certain services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon you visit our website.

You may reject or delete Google Analytics cookies by downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on available here.

Generally you can't delete Flash cookies (also known as local shared objects) with browser controls, but Adobe's website at [www.adobe.com](https://www.adobe.com/) provides information on how to delete or disable Flash cookies. Click here for details.

* * *

### Contact us

Our full details are set out in our privacy policy. You can email us with any questions, queries or complaints at [webdesk@spp-group.com](mailto:webdesk@spp-group.com).

**Thank you for visiting our Sites.**
